<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ML on Machine Learning Case Studies</title>
    <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/tags/ml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ML on Machine Learning Case Studies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/2020L-WB-Blog/tags/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Computer Vision</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-09-explainable-computer-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-09-explainable-computer-vision/</guid>
      <description>What is this blog entry about? Black-boxes are commonly used in computer vision. But do we have to use it? This article looks at this issue and we try to understand it with our small (but developed after one semester of machine learning experience) brains and summarize it here.
What is this article about? Computer vision is cool. But it would be just as cool to understand how it works, and it&amp;rsquo;s not so obvious. Explainable methods of image recognition - which is de facto classification - cannot use logistic regression and decision trees, because every model loses transparency as its performance increases - not to mention understanding neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so famous (yet!) Hajada and his results</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-04-not-so-famous-yet-hajada-and-his-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-04-not-so-famous-yet-hajada-and-his-results/</guid>
      <description>Meet Hajada! Have you heard of the Indian mathematician Hajada? We started to think about it, having read the title of the article &amp;ldquo;The Hajada Imputation Test&amp;rdquo; - it sounded somehow familiar&amp;hellip; But you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t had any contact with him, because not so long ago there was no such man. He was born by the authors of the test and the article, and his name comes from the first letters of their names.
So what is his test? Hajada decided to study the effectiveness and time efficiency of various methods of dealing with missing data. He juxtaposed three simple (or even naive) methods such as deleting rows or inserting random values and three more sublime methods, including mice and missForest algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are black boxes inevitable?</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-01-are-black-boxes-inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-01-are-black-boxes-inevitable/</guid>
      <description>Black vs white Machine learning seems to be all about creating a model with best performance - balancing well its variance and accuracy. Unfortunately, the pursuit of that balance makes us forget about the the fact, that - in the end - model will serve human beings. If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, a third factor should be considered - interpretability. When a model is unexplainable (AKA black-box model), it may be treated as untrustworthy and become useless. It is a problem, since many models known for its high performance (like XGBoost) happen to be parts of the black-box team.
A false(?) trade-off So it would seem, that explainability is, and has to be, sacrificed for better performance of the model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>