<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning Case Studies</title>
    <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Machine Learning Case Studies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/2020L-WB-Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are black boxes inevitable?</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-01-are-black-boxes-inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-06-01-are-black-boxes-inevitable/</guid>
      <description>Black vs white Machine learning seems to be all about creating a model with best performance - balancing well its variance and accuracy. Unfortunately, the pursuit of that balance makes us forget about the the fact, that - in the end - model will serve human beings. If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, a third factor should be considered - interpretability. When a model is unexplainable, it may be treated as untrustworthy and become useless. It is a problem, since many models known for its high performance (like XGBoost) happen to be parts of the black-box team.
Various techniques have risen to counter the threat of unexplainability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a post</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-05-18-how-to-add-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/2020-05-18-how-to-add-post/</guid>
      <description>Posting is really easy. Blog posts are simple Markdown files.
Files The content/post folder is where blog posts are stored. To create a post, add your markdown file to content/post directory with the following format: yyyy-mm-dd-title.md.
Where yyyy is a year, mm is a month, and dd is a day, and md is the file extension representing the format used in the file. For example: 2020-05-18-how-to-add-post.md.
File content An example of a post file you can find here.
A blog post file begins with a front matter which is used to set metadata. For example:
---date: &amp;quot;2020-05-18&amp;quot;title: How to add a postauthors: [&amp;quot;Alicja Gosiewska&amp;quot;]tags:- tutorial---For more authors, add elements to the list, for example [&amp;quot;Alicja Gosiewska&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Second Author&amp;quot;].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About a blog</title>
      <link>/2020L-WB-Blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020L-WB-Blog/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is the result of student projects for Case Studies course at the Warsaw University of Technology. Each team prepared a post on the baisis of one article from the ML Case Studies ebook</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>